Guide to the Hopson family papers, [ca.1900-1980].
Hopson family papers, [ca.1900-1980].
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hopson family papers, [ca.1900-1980].
4247
Hopson family.
14.2 cubic ft.
Farm records and family papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Farm records and family papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hopson family.
Subjects:
Farms--New York (State)--Herkimer County.; Family--New York (State)--Herkimer County.
Places:
Dolgeville (N.Y.); Herkimer County (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Bill Hopson - college papers - 1977-1978 - a special student in College of Agriculture and Life Sciences at Cornell (Box 1)
- Bill Hopson - college papers from SUNY Binghamton ( 1969-1972 ), Colgate ( 1968-1969 ) and as real estate salesman in New York City (ca. 1972-1973 ) and in California (ca. 1975-1977 ?) (Box 2)
- Two envelopes of miscellaneous Hopson & Carpenter financial records, ca. mid-1970s (Box 2)
- Farm - Herd records (registered cows) and financial papers - 1941-early 1970s
  - E.S. Hopson and sons - ca. 1941-ca. 1951 (Box 3)
  - David R. Hopson - ca. 1957-ca. 1968? (Box 3)
  - Hopson and Carpenter - ca. 1968 on (Box 3)
- Edwin S. Hopson papers
  - Grange (Box 3)
  - Miscellany (Box 3)
  - Papers as district school superintendent (Box 3)
  - Check stubs from Elton J. Hopson and Edwin S. Hopson - 1918-1922 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and farm records of Edwin S. Hopson (Box 4)
  - Plays collected by Edwin S. Hopson (Box 5)
- Farm records
  - David R. Hopson - 1960s (Box 5)
  - Hopson & Carpenter - 1970s and 1980s (Box 5)
  - Old folder listing fuel oil purchases - 1953-1957 (Box 6)
  - Folder of receipts from rebuilding barn after 1961 fire (Box 6)
  - Envelope of insurance papers (Box 6)
  - 1971 taxes (Box 6)
  - FICA deposit forms (Box 6)
  - Dolgeville bank ( 1964 ) (Box 6)
  - Social Security DRH (David Robert Hopson) (Box 6)
  - Folder: tax papers - 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - 4 folders - Hopson & Carpenter 1976 financial papers (Box 6)
- David R. Hopson financial records - ca. 1960-1962 (Box 7)
- Packets - checks and accounts of Edwin and Ethel Hopson - ca. 1920s-1940s (Box 8)
- Edwin S. Hopson - Dairyman's League and school superintendent files (Box 9)
- Edwin and David
  - 2 check books - ca. 1954-1956 (Box 9-10)
  - Tax returns - 1960-1965 (Box 9-10)
  - 7 checkbooks - ca. 1960-1966 (Box 9-10)
  - Miscellaneous unsorted papers of Edwin and Ethel Hopson. Most relate to Edwin's school superintendent work but scattered throughout are personal papers. (Box 9-10)
  - Financial records (checkbooks and receipts) - late 1940s-early 1960s (Box 10)
  - Notebooks from late 1940s-early 1960s - includes Edwin's notebooks from education courses at Cornell plus undated notebooks of Edwin's. Also 2 notebooks of Harry Hopson and high school notebooks of Edwin. (Box 11)
- David Hopson
  - College papers from Cornell (Box 12)
  - Financial records from early to mid 1940s (Box 12)
  - Family papers (insurance records) (Box 12)
  - Folder from work on board of directors of Agway (Box 12)
- Herd records, 1970s-1980s - miscellaneous unsorted farm records (mostly herd records and tax records) (Box 13)
- Misc. (Box 14)
- Hopson accounts, 1941-1946 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Written in the hand of David Robert Hopson and Florence Miner Hopson
- Hopson farm sale, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Ledger book, 1916-1918 (Box 16)
- Ledger book, 1920-1925 (Box 16)
- Ledger book, 1930-1934 (Box 16)